NIKHIL DA ROCHA

+91 7350973258 niks77883@gmail.com

A16 Mount N Glory, Kharadi, Pune, 411014

PROFILE

IT Professional with over 5 years of experience specialising in DevOps/SRE. My greatest strength is end to end solutioning and implementation as well as strong focus on customer experience and interactions

GitHub: https://github.com/nikhildarocha

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nikhil-da-rocha-63709358/

EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer, Barclays US, Pune — 2020-Present

- Jenkins, Vault, GoCD Administration and Support.
- Openstack Exit, Migration of GoCd Agents on to VMWare servers.
- Nexus Migration for the application teams.

Platform Engineer, Barclays US, Pune — 2019-2020.

- DC Exit, Modernised services and deployed them on Openshift utilising Jenkins, Consul, Vault.
- Openstack Exit, Built the infrastructure and setup to deploy services on Openshift.

DevOps Engineer, Barclays US, Pune — 2016-2019

- Worked with teams to develop automated scalable deployments using GoCD and Openstack. Leveraged automated testing, monitoring and zero downtime deployments to improve code releases.
- Maintained and enhanced a chef workstation using vagrant and chef that reduced time for developers to install.
- Build the CI/CD infrastructure to deploy services on VMWare servers.
- Built automation around GoCD to avoid Unix intervention in many situations.
- Improved and Championed CI/CD processes by implementing various solutions.
- Migrated the banks core services from a legacy physical infrastructure on to a modern VMWare cluster.
- Worked with 3rd parties and authored and drove the CI/CD implementation of a service on Openstack.
- Worked on a POC to deploy jenkins agents on Openstack.
- Developed terraform modules to deploy services on AWS using chef and scripting tools.

DevOps Engineer, Barclays US, Pune — 2015-2016

- Supporting code releases of the Bank.
- · Providing on call support whenever needed.
- Maintaining and administering the software stack that drives the CI/CD processes
- Integrating and supporting tools like Bitbucket, Sonar, Artifactory, Jenkins, GoCD, Chef
- Built an Intranet Web Crawler to extract the Banks Policies and Standards in one place.

Intern, Siemens Healthcare, Goa — 2014-2014

• Worked in the Supply Chain Management Make Department and built two test Jigs.

Intern, IIT Bombay, Mumbai — 2013-2013

 Worked on a research problem "Linear and Quadratic Chirp Characterization of the Fractional Fourier Transform".

Intern, NIO, Goa — 2013-2013

• Built an H-bridge with direction control using pulse width modulation.

Intern, Tata Communications Limited, Goa - 2012-2012

• Worked in the Optical and Power Systems Department.

EDUCATION

Birla Institute of Technology & Science, Pilani — WILP, 2018-2020 MTech in Software Systems

National Institute of Technology, Goa — BTech, 2011-2015

BTech in Electronics and Communication Engineering

SKILLS

Python, Bash, Ruby, Java, C, Chef, GoCD, Jenkins, Openstack, AWS, Vault, Consul, Terraform, Vagrant, Packer, ELK, Openshift, Docker, Apache, Tomcat, Spring Boot

VOLUNTEERING/MENTORSHIP

• Google Summer Of Code, Jenkins X, 2020